Guide to the Rice Institute Business Manager papers, 1874-1951 UA 353
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Property
  - Blueprints, drawings
    - Sketch showing right of way ditch no. 2 Drainage District no. 12 through the Rice Institute property (Box 30)
    - Rice Institute plat showing proposed alinement of Sunset Road, 1923-04-10 (Box 30)
    - Map (2) showing part of the P.W. Rose and Jos. Gamble sur's, 1908-10 (Box 30)
    - Plat of Sunset Road between Rice Institute and Shadyside, 1917-03 (Box 30)
    - Map showing proposed location of Southampton Sanitary Sewer & Pumping Station, 1923-10-20 (Box 30)
    - Profile of gully, Rice Institute property (Box 30)
    - Industrial building for Mrs. Mellie Esperson Stewart (Box 30)
    - Fraternity Home Addition (2) (Box 30)
    - Sketch showing encrochment on east 1/3 lot 3, O. Smith League, Harris Co. TX (Box 30)
    - Map of Mandell Place subdivision of lot 2, large lot 8 and part of Lamar Place in O.Smith Survey, 1922-03 (Box 30)
    - Map showing portion of Harris County (Box 30)
    - Block no. 688 Ave. A (Box 30)
    - Map of Harris Co., J.B. Chimene Eng. Co. (Box 30)
    - Map showing parts of Pecore 28 acres and Woodland Court Addition in the John Austin two leagues, Harris Co. TX, 1928-01-03 (Box 30)
    - Map showing Rice Institute tract out of great lot no. 3 O. Smith sur., 1924-06-06 (Box 30)
    - Map of Westmoreland Farms, 1911-03-10 (Box 30)
    - Map of Reinerman & Wharton surveys (Box 30)
    - Map showing roads and walks north of Road C (built & proposed) WMR Institute (Box 30)
    - Map showing change in the channel Buffalo Bayou by Fort Bend County Drainage District no. 1 in the William Sypert, Jesse Sitton & John Cunningham surveys (Box 30)
    - Southampton Place (Box 30)
    - Map showing lot no. 6 of the Hollingsworth Subd., Jno. Austin Sur. (Box 30)
    - General plan of fire escape 1107 (Box 30)
    - Southern Structural Steel Co. [fire escape], San Antonio, TX (Box 30)
    - No. 2 Powell District, Navarro Co. TX (Box 30)
    - Plat showing property of W. Waldo, part of lots 6&7 in the W.B. Walker tract (Box 30)
    - Port of Houston, C.A. Elmen & Co. (Box 30)
    - Map showing proposed road from Rice Inst. to Westheimer Road (Box 30)
    - Map of Galveston, TX, 1904-01 (Box 30)
    - Plat showing Cherryhurst (Box 30)
    - Map of Forest Hill (Box 30)
    - Plat showing Cherryhurst proposed storm sewers to be laid by city, 1915-01 (Box 30)
    - Plat showing depredation of industrial on land of the WMR Institute (Box 30)
    - Plot showing blk 3 SSBB (Box 30)
    - Map of Vieweger Heights, Harris Co. (Box 30)
    - Sketch in the Jno. Rienermann League showing the location of the Rice Institute's lands in the west portion of lot #2 of the Bringhurst subdivision of the south half of said Rienermann in Harris Co. (Box 30)
    - Map of 16 6/10 acres of land out of W.R. Baker property in the Hollingsworth survey NSBB Harris Co. as surveyed for the Houston Brick Works Co., 1902-10-10 (Box 30)
    - Sketch showing reflection work on Wm. Rice Institute lands, Tyler Co. TX, 1937 (Box 30)
    - Plat of Southampton, 1923-03 (Box 30)
    - Store building for the Empire Electric Supply Co. (2 sheets), 1924-12-22 (Box 30)
    - Sketch showing right of way ditch no. 2 Drainage District no. 12 through the Rice Institute property (Box 30)
    - Assorted blueprints/drawings unidentified (Box 30)
    - Map of Westmoreland Farms showing location in relation to Houston, TX and the surrounding territory with the various means of access, 1909 (Box 31)
    - Sketch of the subdivision of the Stewart rice farm, 1917 (Box 31)
    - Southern Louisiana showing progress in reclamation of wet prairie lands, 1913 (Box 31)
    - Oberlin tract, LA, approximate estimate of timber; WMR Institute, 1908 (Box 31)
    - Pawnee tract, LA, approximate estimate of timber on the lands of the WMR Institute, 1908 (Box 31)
    - Map of Tyler, TX, ca. 1900 (Box 31)
    - Map of Brady Place, 1912-05-27 (Box 31)
    - Map showing entire acreage cut by Sabine Tram Co., 1916 (Box 31)
    - Table of Louisiana parishes showing timber on WMR Institute land (Box 31)
    - Approximate pine per acre on tract 7.M. (Box 31)
    - Map showing timber cut by Sabine Tram Co., March 29 to Sept. 20, 1915 (Box 31)
    - Map showing timber cut by Sabine Tram Co. from March 20 to Dec. 20, 1916 (Box 31)
    - Report (3) on examination of portion of Weir Lumber Co. lands in Orange and Jasper Cos. TX to WMR Inst., 1909-02-15 (Box 31)
    - Map showing location and amount of tie timber cut by Kirby Lbr. Co. in Smith Survey near Beech Grove, Jasper Co. TX, 1917-06 (Box 31)
    - WMR Institute Houston; Calcasieu & Rapides Parish pine lands, Pawnee Tract, 1907-11 (Box 31)
      Scope and Contents
      Digitized as wrc15497
    - Map of Newton County (Box 31)
    - Map of G.W. Birchfield's subdivision, Jones County, TX, 1909 (Box 31)
    - Eastwood over 200 acres restricted owned and for sale by William W. Wilson Co. (Box 31)
    - Survey in Jasper Co. TX for the WMR Institute, 1912-09-14 (Box 31)
    - Sketch showing approximate topography on Rice Institute lands near Newton, TX in the Polly Youngblood and Moyer surveys, 1914-05-28 (Box 31)
    - Map of Webb Co. TX, 1913 (Box 31)
    - WMR Institute Calcasieu Parish pine land, Merryville tract, 1907-11 (Box 31)
      Digitized as wrc15498
    - Merryville tract (6) timber classifications (Box 31)
    - Pawnee tract (2) Calcasieu Parish, LA, timber classifications (Box 31)
    - Oberlin tract Louisiana timber classifications chart and notes (Box 31)
      Digitized as wrc15496
    - American Lumber Co. situation, 1919-1920 (Box 31)
    - Holdings of the Wier-Reynolds Lumber Co. (Box 31)
    - WMR Institute Calcasieu & Rapides Parish pine lands, 1909 (Box 31)
      Digitized as wrc15495
    - Map showing timber boxed for turpentine by Merryville Naral Stores Co., Merryville, LA, 1913-03-29 (Box 31)
    - Map showing acreage cut from Rice Land Lbr. Co's holdings by American Lbr. Co. and Central Coal & Coke Co.; report no. 1 (3), 1912 (Box 31)
    - Map showing acreage cut from Rice Land and Lbr. Co. holdings by American Lbr. Co.; report no. 2 (2), 1913 (Box 31)
    - Map showing acreage cut from Rice Land and Lbr. Co. holdings by American Lbr. Co.; report no. 3 (2), 1913 (Box 31)
    - Map showing acreage cut from Rice Land and Lumber Co. holdings; delayed report no. 4, 1914-10-28 (Box 31)
    - Map showing acreage cut from Rice Land and Lumber Co. holdings; report no. 5, 1914 (Box 31)
    - Showing timber cut by American Lbr. Co.; report no. 6 (2), 1915 (Box 31)
    - Showing actual govt. acreage cut by American Lbr. Co. and Central Coal & Coke Co.; report no. 7; combines and corrects reports no. 1 to 6 inc. (2), 1915 (Box 31)
    - Map showing American Lbr. Co. cutting in Merryville tract; report no. 8, 1916 (Box 31)
    - Sketch showing American Lbr. Co. cutting, Merryville tract; report no. 9, 1916 (Box 31)
    - Sketch showing timber cut by American Lbr. Co.; report no. 10, 1917 (Box 31)
    - Sketch showing timber cut by the American Lbr. Co.; report no. 11, 1917 (Box 31)
    - Map showing timber cut by the American Lbr. Co.; report no. 12, 1918 (Box 31)
    - Map showing timber cut by the American Lbr. Co.; reports no. 12 & 13 (2), 1918 (Box 31)
    - Sketch showing approximate location, actual count of trees, and scale of windfall in various sections, LA (2), 1912 (Box 31)
    - Sketch showing location of dead and down timber on Rice lands within 2 miles approx. of W.G.Strange Mill (Box 31)
- Series VI: Rincon Field
  - Davis oil properties auditor's reports, 1943, 1945-46 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Starr Co. TX utilization agreements, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Oil Trading Co. agent for Susan J. Carter, 1941-1961 (Box 32, Folder 3-4)
  - Valley Pipeline Co. auditors' reports, 1943-1948 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Starr Co. TX Valley Pipeline stock certificate, 1935-1941 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Starr Co. abstracts, 1942-1943 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Starr Co. supplemental abstracts, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
  - Continental Co. overhead charges, property summary, billing, 1942-1963 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Purchase agreement, releases, 1942, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Accounts with banks, 1942-1947 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Cameron Co. abstract of title, 1941-1942 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Starr Co. abstracts of title, 1941-1942 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Hidalgo Co. abstracts of title, 1935, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Starr Co. title opinions, 1935-1942 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Starr Co. casing head gas agreements & correspondence, 1946-1954 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Starr Co. casing head gas contracts #181-189 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Starr, Cameron, Hidalgo counties agreements, contracts, leases, rights of way, easements, 1935-1960 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Starr Co., Virginia Oil Co. financial records, 1957-1966 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Oil Co. tax records, 1957-1966 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Mercury Petroleum Corp. balance sheets, bylaws, charter, minutes, 1939-1951 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Continental-Rice & Davis inventory & conditions of operations, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 2-4)
  - Felix A. Runion (institute geologist) salary & expense sheets, 1953-1957 (Box 36, Folder 5)
- Series VII: Rice Lumber Co.
  - Stock certificates, 1906-1916 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - Check stubs, 1930-1931 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1906-1921 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Financial ledger pages, 1923-1931 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1935 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Claims against, 1914, 1921 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Land in Mexico; Aldamas Oil Structure, 1922 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Surveys, Tyler Co. TX, 1848-1905 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Deeds, Tyler Co. TX, 1871-1945 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Probate of John O. Trueheart, Galveston, TX, 1875 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - WMR to J.S. Rice, Harris Co. TX, 1907-1930 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Deeds/correspondence, J.S. & WMR, 1891-1910 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Protest notes, First National Bank, 1901 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Judgment with quit claim deed, J.S. & WMR v. Wm. Lee Darling, 1901-1917 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Deeds & leases, Swearingen-J.S. & WMR, Tyler, TX, 1903-1904 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Deed, quit claim deed, agreement, Bradford-Hicks Lumber Co., J.S. & WMR,, Big Brown survey, Tyler, TX, 1917-1918 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Wm. Wiess estate [father of Harry C. Wiess], 1914-1918 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1890-1936 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Taxes, 1911-1940 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Calcasieu Parish, LA, 1908-1917 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Abstract of title & land grant, William Darling, 1885-1910 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Abstract of title & warranty deed, Rice/Ward - Reed, LA, 1879-1906 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Patent, certificate of sale, tax receipt, Rice/Ward - Wm. McMillian, LA, 1888-1906 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Private act of sale, patent, Gulf Land Co., Rice/Ward, LA, 1890-1906 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Deeds, patent, affadavit, correspondence, Rice/Ward -Susie Hill tract, LA, 1899-1906 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Deeds, LA, 1901-1906 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Homestead certificate & mortgage, William Bass, LA, 1902-1906 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Patent, tax receipt, Rice/Ward - S.A. Gourney, A. Brackford, LA, 1904-1905 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Tax receipts, C.C. High, LA, 1905 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Patent, Rice/Ward - John McWilliam, LA, 1905 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Private act of sale, Orange Land Co.-WMR/John C. Ward, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward - Tennislas Reed, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Warranty deed, abstracter's certificates, Rice/Ward - Y.O. Reed, La, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Warranty deed, abstracter's certificates, Rice/Ward - Soloman Reed, La, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Warranty deed, patent, Rice/Ward - McWilliam/Odom, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Warranty deed, patent, Rice/Ward - McWilliam, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Warranty deed, abstracter's certificates, Rice/Ward - E. Naquin, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward - Norbert Mire tract, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Abstract of title, deposition of witness, Rice/Ward - Haas, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward -Arcade Courville tract, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward - C. Duplechain, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Homestead certificate, tutorship of minor heirs, deed, Rice/Ward - Oden/McWilliam, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Warranty deed, C.C. Whitley, LA, 1901-1908 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Abstract of title, Rice/Ward - Chachere tract, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward - Hypolite Reed, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward - Clinton Read, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward - D.W. Stamey, LA, 1906 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Abstract of title with tax certificate, Rice/Ward, LA, 1906-1907 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Warranty deed, Rice/Ward - Seaborn Ballard tract, LA, 1906-1907 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Warranty deed, abstrater's certificates, correspondence, Rice/Ward - Thomas Ballard, LA, 1906-1907 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Mortgage deed, abstract of title, tax receipts, correspondence, Cornelius Duson - WMR, LA, 1906-1909 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Lease, abstract of title, Rice/Ward - Pacific Improvement Co. tract, LA, 1906-1912 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Abstract of title, contract, E.M. Boagni - Rice/Ward, LA, 1906-1913 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Deed, correspondence, Rice/Ward - Alley Bros., LA, 1906-1913 (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Redemption, warranty deed, title, Rice/Ward - Odom/Smith tract, LA, 1907 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Deed with correspondence, Reed & Soileau, LA, 1907-1911 (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Deed, B.F Hughes - Rice/Ward & Wisner/Dresser tract, LA, 1908 (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Abstract of title, Charles Johnson, 1910 (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - Allen, Evangeline, St. Landry parishes, LA, 1909-1942 (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - Abstracts of title, Calcasieu Parish, LA, 1897-1911 (Box 39, Folder 40)
- Series VIII: Legal
  - Union Bank & Trust Co. check stubs, 1906-1913 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Hardeman Irrigation Co. correspondence, 1925-1927 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Hardeman Co. TX deeds/abstracts, 1904-1927 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Hardeman Irrigation Co. ledgers, 1925-1931 (Box 40, Item 4-5)
  - Hardeman Irrigation Co. stock certificates, 1906-1908 (Box 40, Item 6)
  - Hardeman Irrigation Co. warranty deed, contract, porbate of estate of Cecil Lyon, 1926-1928 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Harris Co. TX land survey, John Sleeper & A.L. Harrison, 1838-1899 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Obedience Smith survey abstract of title-Robert Campbell, Ellen Baer, Moses Pottle, Romanza Bailey, Germain Matteson, George Sherick, William Kerlicks, James Perkins, 1885 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Affadavit, E. Tarver for J.W. Pierson, 1886 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum of agreement, WMR-William Grant, 1891 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Application for administratix of estate of Collins McKee, 1872 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Articles of Incorporation, Merchants & Planters Oil Co., 1889 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Bill of Costs, F.A. Rice, 1897-1900 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Certificate of organization, Aetna Soap Machine & Manufacturing Co., 1899 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Abstract of sale, Sabine Tram Co., 1892-1903 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Deeds, 1868-1910 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Depositions of WMR, 1886-1895 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Grantee-grantor, 1847-1897 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Abstract of land, Guadalup Flores survey, 1850-1902 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Insurance, WMR, 1899-1901 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Law suits, 1882-1900 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Memorandum of agreement, WMR - S.A. Kuykendall (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Leases, 1894-1896 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Mortgage, WMR - Charles & Annie Hand, 1890 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Ordinance, Houston Gas Light Co., 1897 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Power of Attorney, James Baker, WMR, Henry Freund, 1891 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Releases, 1888-1913 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - H.H. Lummis, notary public commission, 1901 (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Series IX: South Main Co.
  - Aztex Oil Co. conveyance, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Aztex & Mayan Oil Co. mortgage, deed of trust, conveyance, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Mayan Oil Co. deed of trust, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Mayan Oil Co. extension agreement, conveyance, 1966 (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
  - Mayan Oil Co. production releases, 1968-1969 (Box 44, Folder 3)
- Series X: Trustees
  - Meetings: Sale of timber land, 1908-1909 (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
  - Meeting minutes, 1912, 1930-32 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Meeting minutes, 1932-1933 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Meeting minutes, 1933-1934 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Meeting minutes, 1934-1935 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Meeting minutes (Jan.-June), 1936 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Meeting minutes, 1936-1937 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Meeting minutes, 1937-1938 (Box 46, Folder 7)